<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>Oil prices projected to go down slightly next week</title>
		<author>Alvin Elchico</author>
		<date>May 5, 2022</date>
		<content>Industry players on Saturday projected a slight decrease in oil prices next week, figures that will not be high enough to offset the previous price hike. Diesel prices are expected to drop in the range of P3.10 to P3.30 per liter, gasoline between P0.50 to P0.75, and kerosene from P2.10 to P2.30.Oil prices have seen drastic increases, mainly due to the conflict between Russia and Ukraine, who have major roles in the oil trade. – Report from Alvin Elchico, ABS-CBN News</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>DepEd welcomes passage of Excellence in Teacher Education</title>
		<author>Merlina Hernando-Malipot</author>
		<date>May 20, 2022</date>
		<content>The Department of Education (DepEd) pushed for continued upgrading of teacher education and training as it welcomed the passage of Republic Act 11713 or the Excellence in Teacher Education. “With the passage of this landmark measure, we look forward to radically upgrading teacher education and training towards education quality in the country,” DepEd said in a statement.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>Philippines election: Marcos son eyes return with early lead</title>
		<author>Frances Mao & Tiffany Wertheimer</author>
		<date>May 10, 2022</date>
		<content>The son of a former dictator of the Philippines has taken an early lead in the country's presidential election. If the landslide is confirmed as opinion polls had predicted, the Marcos clan, ousted by a people's revolt 36 years ago, would reclaim power.His main rival is Leni Robredo, a liberal who is currently the Philippines' vice-president. The process could take days before a winner is officially announced, as was the case in 2016. But pollsters in this campaign have consistently shown the Marcos heir ahead with a commanding 30-percentage-point lead.His running mate is Sara Duterte, daughter of the incumbent president, a hardliner who has come to the end of his six-year term in office.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>LOOK: Zack Tabudlo meets LANY’s Paul Klein, Jake Goss</title>
		<author>Dana Cruz</author>
		<date>May 12, 2022</date>
		<content>s a Zack Tabudlo and LANY collaboration in the works? Fans are speculating this as Tabudlo showed himself meeting the American indie pop band. The singer can be seen with LANY members Paul Klein and Jake Goss on his Instagram page today, May 12. Klein had his arm on Tabudlo’s shoulders, while Goss gave an “okay” gesture. Tabudlo did not give further details about the meeting, only captioning it with a shushing emoji.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>Buffalo shooting: Ten dead in attack at supermarket in New York state</title>
		<author>Stephen Belongia</author>
		<date>April 15, 2022</date>
		<content>Ten people have been killed in a shooting in New York state that is being investigated as a racially-motivated hate crime. An 18-year-old man was detained after a stand-off at the scene in the city of Buffalo. Police have not named him. The suspect is believed to have driven for several hours to reach the predominantly black area of the city. Thirteen people were shot and the majority of the victims were black, Buffalo Police Commissioner Joseph Gramaglia said.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>DOH wary of Omicron variant surge</title>
		<author>Kathleen de villa and Nestor Corrales</author>
		<date>May 15, 2022</date>
		<content>MANILA, Philippines — COVID-19 infections and hospitalizations may peak at higher levels, compared to the Delta and Omicron surges, but the Department of Health (DOH) remained cautious in announcing a local transmission of the new Omicron subvariant BA.2.12.1 found in two Filipinos without travel history outside the country. Based on DOH’s projections, the seven-day moving average may reach as high as 7,702 cases and hospital occupancy may go up to 5,512 nationwide in July this year if the variant enters the country.During the Delta surge in September last year, the one-week average peaked at 5,926 and admissions rose to 4,413. Intensive care utilization, meanwhile, is seen to jump by more than 70 percent to 1,124 in July this year from the Omicron peak in January when 652 were admitted on a single day. Health Undersecretary Maria Rosario Vergeire said the Omicron sublineage BA.2.12.1 detected in 14 individuals in Metro Manila and Palawan was found to “most likely exhibit immune evasion,” citing preliminary studies.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>Julie Anne San Jose, Rayver Cruz's tinginan in 'Best Part' video is so malagkit, kilig-worthy</title>
		<author>GMA News</author>
		<date>May 15, 2022</date>
		<content>Julie Anne San Jose and Rayver Cruz are at it again with making everyone so kilig with their latest duet. Apart from their soothing voices that go perfectly together in their “Best Part” cover, what makes it even more worth watching is their super lagkit tinginan. While the two deliver the lyrics to the Daniel Caesar song, it can be noticeable how they would keep on glancing at each other every chance they get. Yes, even while Rayver is so focused on playing guitar.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>Riot sa Quezon City Jail dapat imbestigahan ng PNP, BJMP ayon kay Belmonte</title>
		<author>Chona Yu</author>
		<date>May 14, 2022</date>
		<content>Inatasan ni Quezon City Mayor Joy Belmonte ang Quezon City Police District at Bureau of Jail Management and Penology na imbestigahan ang nangyaring riot sa loob ng kulungan.Ayon sa ulat ng Quezon City Jail Male Dormitory, isa ang patay habang siyam na bilanggo ang nasugatan. “Iniutos na natin ang malalimang imbestigasyon sa nangyaring riot sa Quezon City Jail para malaman ang puno’t dulo nito,” pahayag ni Belmonte.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>‘Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness’ is currently PH’s highest-grossing film of 2022</title>
		<author>Manila Bulletin</author>
		<date>May 13, 2022</date>
		<content>A fortnight after the local theatrical release of Marvel Studios’ Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness, the film is now reported to be the Highest Grossing Film in the Philippines in 2022. Fans of the Marvel franchise expressed their warm reception of the movie as it created new records in the Philippines: the 9th highest opening film of all time for the Marvel Cinematic Universe, 10th in the highest opening of all time for a Disney film, and placed 13th in terms of the highest opening weekend of all time in the local box office. Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness premiered in the Philippines on May 4. It is a sequel to its first installation, Doctor Strange (2016).</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>‘Marcos reveals preference for House Speaker: It's Romualdez</title>
		<author>Ellson Quismorio</author>
		<date>May 13, 2022</date>
		<content>Presumptive president Bongbong Marcos–in a thanksgiving dinner with friends and staff on Friday night, May 13–gave his explicit endorsement of Majority Leader and Leyte 1st district Rep. Martin Romualdez as the House Speaker in the upcoming 19th Congress. A video sent to the Manila Bulletin showed UniTeam bet Marcos talking about the success of their campaign that has led to what appears to be his impressive victory in the May 9 elections. “Of course how can I talk about this without talking about ang ginawa ng tulong ng Lakas, at syempre headed ng ating (the help given by Lakas, of course headed by our) majority floor leader, Congressman Martin, who looks to be set to be the next speaker,” Marcos said. His remarks were met with a loud applause.  House Speaker is elected by members of the House of Representatives at the start of any given Congress. Traditionally, the House members or congressmen go by the choice of the sitting president when it comes to electing their speaker. The current 18th Congress will end on June 2. The House members will elect their speaker on the day that Marcos will deliver his first State of the Nation Address (SONA), which would fall in late July 2022."</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>Mga manggagawa sa NCR at Western Visayas, makatatanggap ng umento sa sahod</title>
		<author>Chong Yu</author>
		<date>May 13, 2022</date>
		<content>Magandang balita para sa mga manggagawa sa sa National Capital Region at Western Visayas.Ito ay dahil sa inaprubahan na ng Department of Labor and Employment ang umento sa sahod para sa mga minimum wage earners. Ayon sa abiso ng DOLE, P33 ang dagdag na sahod sa mga minimum wage earners para sa mga non-agriculture sector. Dahil dito, magiging P570 na ang arawang sahod sa mga non-agriculture sector habang nasa P533 naman ang mga manggagawa na nasa aagriculture sector.Tinatayang nasa isang milyong manggagawa ang makikinabang sa umento sa sahod. Huling nakatanggap ng umento sa sahod ang mga manggagawa sa NCR ay noong 2018.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>SEA Games: Philippines’ Miranda Renner secures bronze in swimming</title>
		<author>Lance Aqaoili</author>
		<date>May 14, 2022</date>
		<content>MANILA, Philippines — Miranda Renner earned the first medal of the Philippine swimming team with a bronze medal finish in women’s 100 meter freestyle in the 31st Southeast Asian Games on Saturday at My Dinh Water Sports Palace in Vietnam. Renner placed third in the contest, clocking 56.950 just a second short from the gold medalist. ingaporean Ting Wen Quah won the gold finishing with the best time of 55.600, while Thai Jenjira Sirs-Ard settled for a silver medal with 56.620.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>Musk says he prefers ‘less divisive’ candidate than Trump in 2024</title>
		<author>Reuters</author>
		<date>May 13, 2022</date>
		<content>WASHINGTON — Billionaire Elon Musk made clear on Thursday that even though he wants Twitter to lift its permanent ban on former President Donald Trump, that doesn’t mean he supports Trump in a prospective 2024 presidential campaign. Musk, the world’s richest person and CEO of Tesla, is attempting to close a deal to acquire Twitter. Musk told a Financial Times conference on Tuesday that Twitter’s decision to ban Trump was “morally bad.” He followed up on those remarks in a tweet on Thursday evening, stressing he does not back Trump as a presidential candidate.</content>
	</blog>

</blogs>

<blogs>
	<blog>
		<title>NDRRMC: 76 reported dead, 29 missing due to Agaton</title>
		<author>ABS-CBN news</author>
		<date>April 14, 2022</date>
		<content>MANILA — The reported deaths from landslides and floods spawned by tropical depression Agaton climbed to 76 on Maundy Thursday, as dozens remained missing, according to the national disaster agency. e National Disaster Risk Reduction and Management Council (NDRRMC) said 72 of the reported deaths were from Eastern Visayas, where a series of landslides devastated communitiesTwenty-nine people were still missing while 8 others were injured, the NDRRMC said. Some 51,000 were still in evacuation centers, while around 162,000 were staying with relatives or friends, after Agaton damaged at least 354 houses, the agency said in its 8 a.m. report. pegged the initial damage to agriculture at around P134 million. Authorities earlier said 26 people died in the coastal village of Pilar, which is part of Abuyog, Leyte, after a torrent of mud and earth on Tuesday pushed houses into the sea and buried most of the settlement. </content>
	</blog>

</blogs>